Hello to everyone watching. Hi. Today
I'm here with the genius, musical
genius, intellectual Ley, and I'm so
honored to be here sitting with her to
discuss her new album, A Matter of Time.
>> Oh, well, the honor is all mine. I'm so
I'm so excited just to like get to hang
out with you.
>> Well, yes, cuz we never get to hang out.
>> I know. So, this is like a very special
treat.
>> So special. Um, I can't wait to like dig
into this album. I listened to it twice
this morning for the first time and it's
amazing. Um, how are you feeling like
ahead of the release?
>> I am. Oh my god. Honestly, I'm I'm
excited but a little bit nervous. I
think
>> this release is like
>> it's like my most honest music yet. And
it's also I think the first time that I
wasn't really thinking too much about
like how to fit into certain molds, you
know? I I think previously I was like
trying to like kind of stick within the
walls of certain genres a little bit.
And for this one I was kind of just like
I don't know. I kind of just believed in
my own genre like the genre of Le if you
will. So yeah, that really shines
through in this album. And I just feel
like I found you and I became a fan of
you because you're bringing genres like
classical and jazz to these like new
generations, right? And you're helping
them find love through those genres. But
I find it so incredible of how Yeah.
with this album you absolutely like pave
your own lane and have this sound. And I
want to know like what sparked that
inspiration to like do that? Did it just
happen or was it like a thought that you
had?
>> I mean originally I mean I have like a
very classical music background. I
started
>> playing cello and piano at a very young
age and
>> and then I just I loved listening to
like Ella Fitzgerald and Nat King Cole
and Billy Holiday. And so when I started
singing I just I always had kind of like
a deeper voice and just resonated with
that. and just those combined along with
like a lot of like music from like
musicals like golden age films. I just I
don't know that was just the music I
loved. But I always felt like a very
>> I I never felt like I was born in the
wrong century I guess. So when I started
making music I kind of just made the
music that felt most
>> natural to me. like it wasn't really
like I couldn't make music that mimicked
the current pop scene because it just
didn't feel like it felt like, you know,
I don't know, it just felt like a sport
that I didn't practice almost.
>> Um, though I enjoy it and would love to
try it. Like at least when I was
starting out, I was just like,
>> I'm going to make the stuff that really
comes very naturally from me
>> and I'm going to try to make make it in
a way that feels
>> current, you know, and not something
that's like super outdated. Like from
the from the very beginning. I was going
to say from the start.
>> From the start. Yeah.
>> Had to catch myself. Um, from the very
beginning I always wanted to
appeal to
just young younger audiences. Like I
wanted to
>> I guess like maybe this is like
something I need to work out in therapy.
I want to appeal to like people my age
and like you know I wanted to
>> introduce this music that I love so much
>> even if it isn't like exactly the songs
like the sounds and the inspirations and
like the chords the harmonic information
like I wanted to introduce that to
>> people my age my friends
>> in a way that felt new and exciting and
not
>> something like I never wanted to
>> play concerts for just, you know, older
generations of people. I I felt like I I
had a hard time finding artists that I
liked that were still touring and, you
know, and made like,
>> you know, cool merch that I wanted to
buy or or, you know, had concerts that I
could go to and be among people that I
had similar values to and and um I don't
know, just like this community.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so yeah. So you had trouble finding
it. So you like became that artist for
other people
>> strangely. Yeah. I think that's usually
how and I'm sure you find that in your
own way too like you become the artist
and the person that you
>> were missing.
>> Yes.
>> You know like you morph into that.
>> Not morph into it. You just like
>> I don't know. I just believe that there
are there are so many people in the
world that you can always
find your people. sometimes they haven't
>> but this was a really long way to get to
this current album and the way that I
wrote it.
>> I really didn't want to think about like
I didn't want to make an album that was
just one vibe the whole time. Like
>> I really want to do a jazz standards
album one day. I want to do like, you
know, classical lullabies, whatever. Um,
but with this song, I just want this
album, I just wanted to write songs that
reflected my emotions at the time that I
was writing them. And then which
whichever genre followed or whichever
sound followed, I just
>> let it live like that. Like I think
>> I I was I didn't want to be limited to a
certain
>> category like at all.
>> Um, because I think that's not really
what being an artist is about. Like I
think limiting yourself like that that's
>> like I don't know that's for machines,
you know.
>> Yeah. Well, I've also seen you talk
about just how like sometimes when
people write songs they think that
they're too personal or maybe like you
know not like they're not open sharing
that information, but I've heard you say
before that like you write this song and
it's like it could help someone and
people can relate to literally almost
any emotion that you have. And I feel
like that's really like prevalent on
this album. Like it's literally like a a
diary.
>> Oh, thank you so much. I Yeah, I I
definitely wanted to kind of showcase
the range of emotion that
>> that women go that I go through, but you
know, also women go through. Mhm.
>> I think I've shown a side of myself to
the world that is very
>> um I don't know quite poised I think and
very like buttoned up and I think you
know I dress the part and I look the
part and I like old music and whatever
and like
>> um
>> but I have
>> lots of anxiety and rage and anger and
confusion and delusion within me
>> that I think I haven't shown the world
before. Like people are shocked when I
swear cuz they're like what? That's not
her.
>> I literally wrote that in my notes. I
was like I love when she swears. It
feels so like cathartic and like
>> it's like Yeah. Well, I I am quite Oh my
god. I said this on a pod. I said this
in some interview and someone was like
it's giving a cause. Like I do cuss a
little um when I say which you know what
whatever it definitely does give that
but like I am a body mouth like I
>> you know I I am a normal 26y old woman
like I say
>> absolutely
>> everything that comes to mind and I have
a messy sense of humor.
>> Yeah. And yeah,
>> but even then I feel like with your past
albums and your past songs, it's like
it's been more poised. So it makes it so
much more like uh like like when on this
album you really get like gritty and you
get angry and there's these emotions
that shine through which to me I haven't
like heard before from you which is so
refreshing and it really feels like it
starts it seems like just the start of
this like new beginning of like a
different but the same like it's it's so
incredible.
>> Oh, thank you so much. Yeah. Yeah. I
wanted the album, the way I sequenced
the album was like it starts with this
>> um with clockwork, which is like
>> a really good reflection of who I show
myself, like who I
>> am to the world, right? It's like this
classic kind of jazzy sounding song that
is very like like I'm on this date and I
don't know what's gonna happen, you
know? and and then with every song like
as it goes on it gets a little more
anxious and and like just a little bit
more surreal I want to say.
>> And then the very last song on the album
is like an explosion of just like all of
the emotions and all the sounds, all the
instruments played on the album just
like piling over each other and it's
just a catastrophe. And
>> to me, it's like
kind of a a metaphor. I don't know if
that's even the right word, but it's
kind of a metaphor for like getting to
know a person, right? It's me. I'm
showing myself to the world, but it's
also it's an album about falling in love
and the process of falling in love and
how
>> you can't hide yourself from anybody for
very long. You know, that was one of the
most I think shocking things that I went
through falling in love for the first
time. Like
>> you can only hold up that like kind of
character for so long that that facade
of perfection doesn't stay up for very
long. Like no matter how hard you try.
>> Yeah. And so that the way that the album
is sequenced like both lyrically, but
musically especially is that it just
like is something perfect that you just
pull at and it just like completely
comes unraveling.
>> So would you say that this album is like
the first time that you've really like
fallen in love and like telling that
story?
>> Definitely. Yes. I think my last albums
were like explorations of like what is
love like and I think I'm in love but
I'm not sure like I might be in love.
>> This was definitely the first time where
I was like falling in love and learning
about myself in the process.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> so it was really
>> like like a really fun thing to to to
write about and navigate. And you know,
I've always written about love, but
funnily enough, I've never I'd never
been in love before.
>> So, it was really it was really cool. It
was fun.
>> Specifically with Clockwork, you said
how like it's kind of like this spiral
into like the more anxious feelings. Do
you think like anxiety and nervousness
is like a big part of love for you? Like
does it play a big role? Yeah.
>> Yes. I'm so anxiously attached.
I don't think a single girl
that isn't anxious or avoidant.
>> Oh girl, I'm the same.
>> Or both.
>> Yeah,
>> for the heck of it.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
Yeah. It's kind of just when you when
you grow up and you nobody had a
>> if nobody had a crush on you growing up,
you know,
>> no girl or guy showed you that kind of
romantic attention,
>> you just like don't even
>> believe it.
>> You don't believe it. You don't put
yourself in the competition. You don't
even put yourself in the lineup. You've
never been in the lineup.
>> Yes. Which I really I don't want to get
ahead of myself, but Snow White, like
that's my favorite song on the album.
That's my favorite song.
>> I was saying on my Really?
>> Yeah.
>> I was saying on my way here, it's my
favorite song on the album. I listened
to it twice this morning and I cried
both times because truly what you just
said like about um no one having a crush
on you growing up and not feeling like
enough even now in young adult life when
it's like I should be like I don't know
accepting this love. But it's really
hard if you I know you say in the song
like I don't feel pretty enough and it's
like it's not up for debate which
>> I want you to talk about that lyric
because
>> Yeah. Oh my god. I mean I feel like Snow
White is one of those songs that I wrote
and didn't
kind of try to control the words that
were coming out.
>> Okay. Like I think I've written songs
about self-reflection and self-image
before, but I was always
>> hyper aware of sending a good image out
to the my audience, which is, you know,
largely comprised of of young women of
>> I I mean of of young people, you know,
and I never
>> I never wanted to send some sort of
message from on top of some hill being
like,
>> "Hey, like it sucks up here, too, you
know,
>> and wanted to kind of like be a role
model in that I to show people that I
accepted myself in hopes that they
accept themselves.
>> But if I'm being completely honest,
which with this album I'm being the most
honest I've ever been, like
>> it just doesn't always feel like that.
It actually very very rarely feels like
that. I think
>> I I've never been like the prettiest
girl in class. Like I never was. That
was never that was never my thing. I was
like
>> I knew I was like
>> good at music. Yeah. You know, like I
was like the I knew my thing and I was
confident enough in my thing, but
>> it was really Yeah. Snow White.
I just like poured my heart out.
>> And it's very It's kind of mean. Like
the song is like not nice. It's like I
talk about skinny always winning and
like and I'll never have enough of it.
>> Mhm.
>> And
and it's kind of true. Like I don't
know. I like didn't
>> I think in the past year I've had or
past like two whatever years of this
career like
>> I've been flung into the most incredible
but crazy scenarios that I never
imagined that I'd see myself in. and,
you know, walking red carpets and like
squeezing into sample sizes of designers
and and kind of, you know,
being standing side by side with these
like gorgeous women that I've
>> seen in the spotlight my whole life.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's it's really really hard to like
find confidence in yourself in those
moments, I think.
>> Yeah. And
I had a couple of moments this year
where I just was feeling really awful
about myself and also really awful about
my body.
>> Yeah.
>> I think there's like this
>> I think that often times women
>> who think too much. I I don't know. I
think I often times feel really shitty
talking about not liking my body. Yeah,
>> because that is so classically female
and so
>> like boring. Like everybody feels that
way. We know that, but we know that very
quietly, you know, like we know that in
secret.
>> And
>> I just like
>> I don't know. I was just like comparing
myself to
everybody that I was seeing around me
and being like, I am bigger than them.
>> Yeah. or like I am not as pretty as them
or
>> like for I like don't
I don't know.
>> Yeah.
>> Like it's it's so mean to myself to
write a song like that. But I kind of
like my hope is that there's comfort in
the consolation of knowing that others
feel the same.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. You know when you're having like
a really bad day.
>> Yeah.
>> And none of your friends can really talk
you out of it. Like no one's going to
talk you out of your
>> slump. But
The best thing to hear when you're
feeling shitty about yourself is like a
friend being like, "Well, I feel really
awful about myself, too."
>> And then you just feel awful together.
>> Yeah. So then usually does it feel it
makes you feel better when like you see
your fans connecting
>> Oh my god. Music
>> so much. Yeah. I mean that I mean that's
one of the reasons I love writing music
so much. like writing songs, writing
very personal lyrics because when a fan
comes to me and says that they've
listened to the song and and resonate
with it in some way, it makes me feel
less crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> Cuz I'm like, "Oh, good. I'm not the
only one."
>> Yeah.
>> Um but I digressed from that line before
the um the it's not up for debate line.
That one's like a bit of a double
entandra for me because I think
the first was I just like
there are so so many times where I feel
like my body is valued higher than my
voice.
>> Whether it is my body my voice as a
speaker like what I have to say or like
me as a singer I just feel like
>> oh maybe I'd be more successful if I
were prettier or something like that.
Um, but then also I feel like yeah,
people just don't always want to I feel
like I feel like beauty is sometimes
valued higher than
>> than intellect or
>> you know
>> or conversation skills or or personality
or whatever. And I I think I really
>> I feel that in
>> I feel that in LA. I feel that in New
York especially. And
>> and
>> I hate it. I hate it so much. It feels
like this like completely inescapable
fate.
>> Yes, I I agree. And I feel like
mentioning LA and New York, I feel like
especially in the public figure space,
>> it gets pretty bad just in terms of
people perceiving you. And like I don't
know about you, but for me, I feel like
I was more confident when I was younger.
Even though I wasn't the prettiest girl
in the room, I didn't really
>> Yeah.
>> care until it got to a certain point
where I got older and the feeling kind
of progressed.
>> How has like I don't know just like
societal pressure and like now being in
the public has that like made it worse
and harder to face?
>> I Yeah, I think so. I mean, I think I've
always been hard on myself. Like I
definitely grew up like
very awkward and
>> and kind of like I remember crying
because I didn't like how I looked when
I was like a teenager, but it all felt
very like teenager.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
>> And now it's like a completely different
layer. It's like seeing a photo of
myself,
>> right,
>> on stage from like or like on a
red carpet or something from like an
angle that I didn't like in a moment
where I was really stressed and
>> and having
>> Yeah. like millions of eyes on my
features,
>> you know, like I like got Invisalign
this year and and like you know, all of
a sudden I noticed that I I thought I
had straight teeth my whole life
>> and like all of a sudden like
>> I felt like compared to everyone around
me in LA that my teeth weren't that
straight.
>> So now I have like
>> I'm wearing like plastic in my
Yeah.
Um, like it's like little stuff like
that. I think I've definitely like I
know every part of my face now. Like I
know where my
>> where my jaw is like not aligned or
whatever. Like all these little things
that don't matter at all and I
didn't care about before, but now I've
seen because I've seen so many photos of
myself.
>> Yeah.
>> And I really really hate that. I don't
think that's natural and I wish there
were a way to like
I see myself in these situations and get
photographed, but really that's just
everybody now. Like
>> everyone's taking photos of each other
constantly. Like we're always on camera.
>> Yeah.
>> Right now we're on camera from three
angles.
>> Three angles. Exactly. And it's like am
I sitting upright? like is my arm out?
You know, it's it's
>> my posture. I know it's bad, but we're
just not going to think about it.
>> Um,
>> yeah, it's it's hard. Like, it's really
>> I wish I I wish I could sit here and
tell you that I was completely confident
with how I looked and and it didn't
matter. And and I I don't feel that way.
Hence why I wrote Snow White.
>> Well, yeah. And there's so many people,
specifically girls, cuz it really does
like put emphasis on like the experience
of being a girl.
>> Um like there's specific lines I
remember that like put emphasis on that
like
>> Yeah. Well, it's like
>> Yeah. I mean the whole whole being a
woman and feeling like it's
>> nobody wants to hear from a woman. They
just want to see a woman.
>> Yeah. And I think that it'll connect.
>> Oh, I hope so. So, no, I it connected
with me immediately and
>> that means a lot.
>> It's really my favorite song. It's so
beautiful.
>> It's Yeah, it's very It's also The
reason it's called Snow White is because
Snow White was actually based on an
Icelandic woman.
>> Oh, really?
>> Like the illustrator was from
>> I think he may have like immigrated to
Winnipeg or something.
>> Oh, Canada.
>> Canada lore.
>> Canada lore. Yes. Well, like in the
early 1900s, like 20% of the Icelandic
population went to Winn like moved to
Winnipeg.
>> So, there's like a little Iceland there.
>> Okay.
>> Um, which I'm kind of curious to visit.
>> You should
>> because I just love Iceland lore.
>> Mhm.
>> But, um, anyways, I don't know if that
was the exact connection, but
>> he was his parents were Icelandic. He
was in love with an Icelandic woman, and
so he like drew Snow White after her.
Okay.
>> And so I thought that was like kind of
really appropriate because one of the
reasons I never really felt like I fit
in growing up was I was like one of the
very few Asian kids in my school. Like
literally everyone had blonde hair and
blue eyes
>> and I just felt like I stuck out so
much. I felt
>> like such a foreigner. Um
>> so
>> yeah, amazing song. I love it so much
and I think that everyone will love it
so much. I I hope so. That's
>> Yeah, that's going to be like the lead
>> song with the album.
>> Should I play you the
>> Lover Girl perhaps? Cuz I kind of
skipped over her cuz I got excited.
>> Oh my god. Snow White. But
>> no, I I always get excited about Snow
White. It's also one of those songs
that's really easy to talk about cuz I
have a lot to say. Yeah,
>> I could write like I could write a whole
another Snow White like verses and
chorus.
>> Yeah,
>> cuz I have so much to say on that
specific matter.
>> Well, I feel like it's just an endless
topic that you can talk about cuz
there's so many feelings in
>> I think everybody feels that way.
>> Well, that was another like
the the skinny always wins. I'll never
have enough of it is because like I I
actually do fundamentally believe that
even if I
were this idea of perfection that I have
that I see in my head, I still wouldn't
be satisfied.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I think it's I don't think anybody
really is completely satisfied.
>> No. And I've been there. Like I feel
like I've reached a point where I'm like
I should think that I'm like this
perfect idea of myself that I had in my
head, but I still don't think that you
feel fulfilled cuz it's just like
ultimately
>> you can do all of that.
>> Oh,
>> no. I know. I think you know the most
perfect girl to you
>> Yeah.
>> is out there thinking of a girl that is
perfect to them.
>> Yeah.
>> And feeling insecure about something.
Yeah. So,
um, okay. Should we play Lover Girl?
>> Yes.
>> I feel like that's such a tour song with
the clapping.
>> I We rehearsed it for the first time,
uh, with my band like a couple days ago.
>> Okay.
>> And it was so fun.
>> So fun.
>> Yeah. This is a fun one. I I wrote it
when I was in Tokyo.
>> Okay.
>> And I was missing a certain someone,
>> right?
>> And I was like,
wh why? What? Why have I done this?
>> Why am I being in love right now?
>> Because
>> it hurts.
>> Like when you're away from the person
that you love, you're like, "Oh my god,
this sucks."
>> Yeah.
>> And I think I've been pegged as this
like hopeless romantic girl.
>> I've definitely been pegged as the
hopeless romant for good reason. Like I
definitely wrote music about that.
>> Yeah. And um you know I I also believe
that hope being a hopeless romantic is
like a full like lifestyle like I think
it's an air
>> but
>> do you think it's like a phase or do you
think it's a lifelong
>> I think
>> journey
>> I think it always starts with like true
like hopeless romanticism but I think
other than that like
>> being a hopeless romantic is simply
being an optimist.
>> Yeah. Like I think it's just seeing the
good in situations and wishing for the
best.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's what I like to the core that
is what being a hopeless romantic is.
>> Yes.
>> So I you can be in love and in hope and
a hopeless romantic at the same time.
>> I agree. I think that it's about passion
too. Like you just like
>> it is about passion.
>> It's about like pouring all your love
into one person. Even if
>> you're with that person, it's still like
>> or even if it's not reciprocated. Yes.
Well, that's the Yeah,
>> that's the classic.
>> That's the classic. Yeah. Which
>> you had that era and now you're in this
new era where it is reciprocated.
>> It is reciprocated.
>> And like was that like a gradual
realization or you said you were in
Tokyo. Was it just like oh my god I'm
this person now?
>> Yes. I kind of Yeah. I was like I have
become first of all I was like ew. I was
like, I've become
>> this person that I would have made fun
of,
>> right,
>> in the past.
>> Yeah.
>> Like this lover girl.
>> Um, and that's why I'm like, what a
curse it is to be a lover girl.
>> Yeah.
>> Obviously, it's not a curse. Like, it's
great, but being a lover girl is being a
hopeless romantic. It's like,
>> and sometimes I feel like it can be
torture.
>> Oh, it's it's torture. It's a curse.
It's like
>> and then there's a bridge in this song
which I've never written a song like
this kind of like this like bosanova
style that has a bridge.
>> So I had a lot of fun doing that. We
made it really like dreamy and surreal.
And that was kind of about me having
this like fever dream on stage where I
was like oh my god I think I see him in
the wings like and I I wait by the phone
like a high school movie. It's like
>> Yeah.
>> It's disgusting.
>> Are you a daydreamer? I'm I am
>> okay. Yeah. Um
>> famously
>> Yeah. Are your like are a lot of your
songs usually like the product of
daydreaming and now it's like more real
or even on this album like are there any
daydreaming songs where
>> There are definitely some daydreaming
songs. I mean not all the songs are like
completely like from bred from my exact
experiences. like many of them are
inspired by um but they're not like all
factually correct like playbyplay
exactly what happened.
>> I do love a sense of ambiguity.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> a lot of them are like based on
conversations I have with my friends
about like
>> our loved lives. It's very um
>> it's Yeah. A lot of sometimes it's just
like a song or a lyric that I think of
and I'm like, "Oh, I've felt that way."
Or
>> Yeah.
>> You know?
>> Sometimes with like breakup songs. Well,
there are some breakup. I did I did go
through a breakup.
>> Mhm.
>> Before I met
my person.
>> Yes.
>> That um that kind of like shattered me a
bit.
>> And so I did write about that. Well, I
was going to say there are definitely
like breakup vibe songs, which kind of
shocked me cuz I just assumed I made the
mistake of assuming that it would be
like a fully like loveydovey
head in the clouds album.
>> It's not very loveydovey at all.
>> No,
>> it's it's very anxious.
>> Yeah.
>> Um Yeah. This one's for the anxiously
attached.
>> Yeah. But um yeah, I mean
I feel like even in love you go through
heartbreak, you know, and if you're a
dramatic person like me,
>> you put yourself through it.
>> Yeah. Um, yeah, I definitely I've I've
been through some heartbreak and and you
know, revisited past kind of experiences
and
>> took lyric fragments that I'd jotted
down from, you know, months before and
>> Yeah. Do you find that um being like an
artist and songwriter helps you navigate
your anxious attachment and like find
out more about it or is it just kind of
like
>> Yeah, I think I at least
get to like put my thoughts into words
>> and create something out of it that will
hopefully resonate, but also like I
think I organize my thoughts by writing
songs about them. Mhm.
>> Cuz I'll like I'll put my thoughts into
a song and then I'm like, "Oh, it maybe
it was just that."
>> Yeah.
>> Just a little spiral that turned into a
song.
>> Yeah. But um but yeah, it's it's a funny
thing like navigating being a songwriter
and
you know having all these feelings and
like trying to channel them into like
the correct
like the correct songs
>> if that makes sense.
>> No, that makes so much sense. I
completely understand. Um and you said
you wanted to incorporate clapping in
the track. What was like the inspo
there? The inspo was well I was just
listening to like the different
percussion elements of bosanova of
Brazilian music and there is
>> clapping occasionally and I've never had
a clapping song
>> and my fans are so engaged in concerts
>> that I was like I want to give them
something to like do with me.
>> Um so I was definitely thinking about
like the live experience of that song
which is why I'm so excited to play
Lover Girl live. Um,
>> yeah.
>> Do you have a song you're most excited
to play live?
>> Play live
>> on the upcoming tour.
>> Let's see. I mean, that No. Yeah, we're
announcing it in a week, so we'll be
>> okay. Okay.
>> On the upcoming tour.
>> Yeah. I mean, which I mean, the tour is
like a huge
reason why I like
the the tour was like a big factor in
how I wrote this album. Like I knew I
was going on
an arena tour and playing these kind of
big vast rooms and I was thinking about
how I could fill into them. I mean, not
only with like volume, but like with
like storytelling and and things like,
you know, clapping and and just like
maximizing the sound kind of on all the
songs like
>> having dense string writing and and
drums and placing them in a very
intentional way. Um, so yeah, the tour
I'm really excited for. Let's see. What
am I excited to play live? I am
I mean honestly Lover Girl. I'm really
really excited. I'm excited about
Clockwork too cuz I think I'm going to
>> find a way to make it really theatrical.
>> Yes. With like the ticks. The clock
ticks. The clock tick. The clock tick.
>> Yeah. Um. Ooh. I'm excited to play Clean
Air Live. I think it's important to note
that under my notes for clean air, I
wrote wow with five
W's. Um because
>> and then instrumental exclamation mark
because this one is so good.
>> Oh, thank you so much.
>> It's so good. It's very spring. It feels
like an exhale to me. That's exact.
That's a beautiful way to describe it
cuz that's definitely what it felt like.
I I wrote it actually at the end of I
wrote it when I was in Iceland over the
holidays and it was at the end of my
kind of like really crazy touring year
and
also had gone through, you know,
emotional, you know, up and downs and I
just somebody asked me like, "Oh, how
are you doing?" My manager asked me, he
was like, "How are you doing over there
in Iceland?" And I was like, "You know,
I feel like I'm breathing clean air."
And I was like, ding, ding, ding.
>> That could be a song.
>> Yes.
>> So, I wanted to That's why there's like
3 hours of sunlight kind of those lyrics
because
>> there are only 3 hours of sunlight in
Iceland during the winter.
>> Um, but also the air in Iceland's
really, really clean. Yeah. So,
>> but I wanted to write a song just about
getting rid of all the bad juju in your
system,
>> right? whether it was, you know, whether
it's like a a bad boyfriend or a bad
work situation or like literally like an
exam that you're so happy you finished.
>> Um, I just wanted to write a song about
how about getting something out of your
system and how,
>> you know, sweeter pastures are waiting
for you.
>> Yeah. Well, I feel like at the beginning
of the song, it's like you talk about
physically cleaning space, but it's like
>> seems like a metaphor for like
emotionally cleaning out space as well.
>> Yep. Um, and also I feel like it might
not have been the intention with the
song, but it also does give like
seasonal depression vibes in a way where
it's like you're finally I just got out
of like a brutal Montreal winter where I
didn't see the sun for however long
>> and I'm pale and I feel just and I feel
like this song I was listening to it
today and I was in the sun by the pool
and I was like this is what this feels
like is getting out of that like
seasonal depression. It totally is that.
I mean, it's literally talking about
like
>> like the cold and how it's like this
this hollow winter tide. Like that's
literally one of the lyrics because it
is
>> kind of about that. And and I like you
grew up in kind of an endless winter and
then that little
>> I I I guess I did want to write a song
that kind of musically painted that
feeling of like a summer day
>> when you live in a really wintry place.
Yeah,
>> like that first, you know, that first
nice day and everyone comes crawling out
and people are like filling up the
streets and it's like
>> never hot enough to be wearing like
shorts and sandals, but everyone's
wearing shorts and sandals like and it
feels like there's just like some sort
of like drugs in the era cuz everyone's
out and happy for the first time. Like I
wanted to write a song that was kind of
like that.
>> Is it like that in Iceland? Like is that
the Cuz it's like that in Montreal. Like
the second there's a nice day. Everyone
and their mom is outside and it's the
best feeling ever.
>> Yeah. Iceland just had one of those days
like a couple days ago and it was like
>> cuz I read the Icelandic news
>> every day cuz it kind it gives me a
sense of home but they also
>> um put together the most important
points in the world news.
>> Yeah.
>> So I could just like read it there. But
>> yeah,
>> the whole like all the headlines were
like suns are sun's out, sales are good.
Like they were talking about how like
just like in general like people like
buy more stuff when the weather's good.
They're like out eating at restaurants
and stuff and I thought it was really
cute.
>> Yeah. Um, but yeah, I also was listening
to like a lot of like the Dolly Parton,
Emmy Lou Harris, um, uh, Linda Ronstat
album,
>> and I love that kind of
>> that country threepart harmony is just
so satisfying,
>> and I wanted to write a song that had
kind of that almost like country twang
to it. Um
>> well yeah like what's the production
process for a song like this where it's
like the instrumental is so beautiful
>> and it's just like what do you what's
your process? What do you do first and
like
>> Yeah. I mean for every song on this
album except for Cautionary Tale I just
wrote the song
>> okay
>> on my own at home and then when I
finished it I brought it to Spencer my
producer producer. Yes. And we kind of
like perfected it from there and add add
string arrangements and and Spencer is
usually the one to kind of like figure
out the right bass sound and the guitar
sound and piano sound and so we kind of
you know
>> Yeah.
>> make it perfect from there.
>> Okay. Yeah. Well, Spencer has worked
with you on the past two albums as well.
>> This was this is my third album with
Spencer.
>> Was it like a different process for you
guys as like working as a team? Was
there anything new? any new challenges
that were brought up or totally. I mean,
>> is it just kind of like a flow for you
guys at this point?
>> It's definitely a flow for some things.
I mean, like Lover Girl, I brought the
song in and we like did it in a day.
Like, we're so locked in with certain
sounds. There's some songs that I
definitely had like a
kind of clear vision for, but it took a
little longer to figure out because it's
like playing around with new sounds and
>> and I think we definitely like pushed
each other really really hard on this
album, but in like a really satisfying
good way. I really wanted to continue
working with Spencer because I think I
didn't want to make one album that, you
know, I didn't want to make one album
that was like semisuccessful or whatever
and then just like, you know, off
and work with somebody and completely
change somebody else and completely
change my sound. Like
>> I definitely wanted to work with Spencer
and see how we could push the limits of
our sound together.
>> Yeah. Um, but Spencer gets me in a way
that I don't like there's no other
producer that understands me like
Spencer does. So, it was it felt like
such a safe nest to kind of bring new
ideas to and and experiment and
>> it was Yeah.
>> How did you guys connect? Like, how did
you find each other?
>> I was just kind of like doing producer
rounds. had this album of songs which
eventually became Everything I Know
About Love, my first album.
>> But it was just yeah, just this book of
voice memos and and songs that I had
written and wanted to find the right
kind of person to write producer to
>> bring them to light and like make them
real songs. And
>> it was hard because
>> I wanted somebody who understood jazz
music better than me. Yeah,
>> someone who understood
>> classical music better than I did and
had like experience with like string
because I play cello on all my songs.
Like it's very
>> important to me that whoever I work with
cares about the same music as me,
>> but then on top of that, I wanted to
work with somebody who also had an
understanding for pop production or or
rock music in a way that I didn't, you
know.
So, it was definitely a fun challenge
trying to find the person that had all
of those. But I found that in Spencer
just like I remember I brought we worked
on a song of mine called uh Questions
for the Universe.
>> Okay.
>> And he wrote the most beautiful string
arrangement for it. That is I mean and
that is it exists
>> in the state that we recorded in. And I
remember I was just like wow like this
is it.
>> And I hadn't even heard him do anything
else. I could just like tell that we
were like magnets.
>> Um, so I'm really really
>> I'm really really thankful for him and
>> and it's been Yeah, it was super fun to
get to work with him
>> on this one again. And I feel like every
year I go back to his studio. He's added
like new instruments and he's learned so
much about music that I care about and
kind of added to his vocabulary in a way
that is I can tell he like cares so so
so much. So I'm really thankful for
>> all the kind of extra like he has like
stacks of composition books on his on
his table on his desk and
>> and um and it's so fun to get to just
like nerd out with him as well.
>> Yeah. Um, I also read that you worked
with Aaron Destner on this album and I
must know which songs and how that was
cuz I'm a huge fan of his and I feel
like he's really good at like
>> bringing out this side of artist that's
so much more like fleshed out and just
like bare almost like and I can really
see that in this album and I'm Yeah, I'm
so curious as to how it was working with
him.
>> Oh my god. I was like, well, first of
all, like obviously I'm such a Swifty,
so and I love
>> like Folklore and Evermore were the
songs that the albums that kind of make
me really love her music.
>> Yes.
>> And really respect her as as a as a
lyric writer. And
>> so going to Long Pond was like so cool.
And I love the National as well.
It's so fun cuz Aaron has an identical
twin brother who is a classical
composer.
>> Really?
>> So there was like so much random
crossover.
>> Really?
>> All four of us share a birthday.
>> Wait, that's pretty nuts.
>> Kind of crazy.
>> That is crazy.
>> And you can tell there's like maximum
Taurus energy happening in the session.
like working with Aaron was so fun and
it completely like
re I got to completely change the way
that I think about music and production.
I I brought one song to him which is
Castle in Hollywood
>> which I wanted to talk about.
>> Okay. Well, we'll get there. We'll
definitely get into that. Um and then he
had these kind of like musical sketches.
um that he was like, "Do you want to try
writing over one of these?" And I've
never done that before.
>> Um but with Cautionary Tale, I wrote
kind of like over one of those and it
like pushed me musically in a way that
was so refreshing and something I really
really needed. And I had so much fun
working through that with him and adding
strings and kind of like I don't know
just like having a different approach to
making a song that still felt so honest
to myself. It was just really fun.
>> So yeah. Wait, should we play maybe?
>> Yes.
>> The songs that I did with Aaron.
>> Um a big friendship breakup one. I feel
like I'm gathering that. Um, is there a
difference between Cuz it sounds like a
love song, but like a I think that it
sounds like a love song in a way where
like you know
>> you love this person or you loved this
person and it's like the same breakup
vibe but is it different writing a
friendship breakup song versus just
>> totally. Yeah. I mean, at least in my
experience, everyone experiences this
differently, I think, but in my
experience, like
>> having a friend break up with like a
female friend,
>> it's like I still wish
them the best
>> in a way that I like I like when a guy
me over, I'm like, I don't I
literally don't want to think about you
or talking to you ever again.
>> But with the girl, I'm like I'm like,
wow. like we had such a fun thing going
and it didn't work out and I care so
deeply about you.
>> Yeah.
>> And
but I like we can't be friends.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and it feels like
>> I like this is a song of like lamenting
a certain time in my life and and kind
of wishing that things wouldn't have
gone
>> Yeah.
>> in a gone in a bad direction and wishing
that we could kind of like hold on to
that. I think for me specifically, I had
like this friendship breakup around a
time that really it just felt like kind
of like the last of my girlhood.
>> Like I feel like my trust was breached
in a way that
>> I never really looked back after that. I
felt kind of always had my guard up
after that.
>> And so like that's mainly what I'm upset
about. But yeah, I don't know. I feel
like everyone I know has gone through a
bad friend breakup and it hurts in a
really weird way. Like hits you
sideways.
>> Yes. Very. And I feel like the lyric
like marked the end of our girlhood.
Like that's a whole era and it's like do
you look back on that era now with like
>> positive
>> energy or
>> Yeah. I mean I I totally do because it
was so defining and it's made me who I
am. And I lived in this castle in
Hollywood. I lived in this like
apartment that was like I lived in a
circular bedroom like with a turret and
and I remember we like talked about how
it was like this
amazing fairy tale that we had come to
find each other and then that we I think
you know we we take something from every
person that comes into our lives like we
pick up habits or ways they dress or you
know even there are ways in in which I
speak like there There are things I say
and do that are directly
taken from
>> Absolutely. Yeah.
>> And so in a way I see a little bit of
her in myself all the time. And so I
kind of just
>> wanted to write a song about that
experience. And
>> I I very purposely purposefully wanted
it to be
>> kind of like an upbeat pop song almost.
Um, I mean it still has like that those
chord progressions that are very le and
like you know if you strip it back it'll
probably sound you know very much like a
Le song. I mean it is a le song but
>> it has those strings and it has like
that minor cliche in the bridge that
make it very
>> that's like that tinge of sadness just
in the bridge but other than that it
sounds like a really happy song and I
love like that justosition because at
the end of the day I don't really look
back at it as something really really
really
>> like sad. I kind of look back at it and
I was like that was a sweet moment in my
life and I hope you're well.
>> Yeah. Well, I loved even just the title
and like that idea of like Castle in
Hollywood where like you said it's like
>> it was so magical and it was this period
that was like um it was supposed to last
forever as you say in the song and I
think I don't know I just so many people
have been through that especially girls.
I've had my like
>> couple of friendship breakups that have
like shaken me to my core, but then as
time goes on, like you said, it just it
becomes more of like looking back at it
positively, which I feel like this song
perfectly encapsulates.
>> I guess that this was my attempt to look
at it positively. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um and then I can definitely hear
the the Aaron in there, too.
>> Yeah. No, I love his like
>> he has this like little like guitar like
thing like Okay, that was bad. But like
he his production is so clearly him and
I had so much fun like meshing our
worlds together.
>> Um
>> which I can also speak about further on
a cautionary tale. Yes. Um, so a
cautionary tale I just
I want I had the I had the words or the
title a cautionary tale written on my
notes app for like
>> months because I was like, "Oh god, like
that was such a cautionary tale. Like
this is like what I'll tell all my
friends forever."
>> And so I was like, "That's a really good
song title." And so I gathered kind of
my own and my sisters.
>> My god. my own and my sister and my
cousin's experience together into this
song. But
>> it's ultimately a song about how it's a
song about being a giver
>> and giving someone all of yourself and
and not really having it and not really
having them receive it.
>> Yeah. you know, and
also I kind of just any person who's
done me wrong in any way, I just like
see a child within them that is
>> not that and wouldn't have done this and
like
>> there's something along the way that
made them the way they are. And so I
guess in a way it was my way of trying
to forgive.
>> Yeah,
>> that's also one of my favorites.
>> Oh, I'm so honored. I love a song that's
about like feelings coexisting and I
feel like this is that where it's like
there is empathy in there.
>> Yeah.
>> But there's also anger.
>> Mhm.
>> Is that like hard to write about those?
Like
>> No, because I think that's I've never
been able to be just one. Like I've
never been able to be completely angry
at somebody cuz I always see
>> I always see a side
>> to it, you know?
And that's kind of what I was like
trying to illustrate with the um bridge
being like you there's a guiltless child
who never saw his mother's smile like
>> there maybe there's just a part of you
>> that
>> made you this way and it's not really
your fault and it's
>> you know society's fault or something. I
don't know.
>> Um where you're trying to please
somebody inside of you that you'll never
be able to please.
>> I don't know. So it it is like it seems
like it's a juxtaposition, right? Both
being angry and being empathetic, but I
feel like every
>> aside from tough luck, honestly.
>> Yeah.
This is like the breakup song that has
that level of empathy in it because I'm
like,
you know,
singing about how
it it is at part my fault for being a
chameleon, like having my chameleon
heart. It's kind of,
>> you know, it was me being like, why am I
>> I I'm smart. I've always been the smart
one, so why did I do this? Why did I
change myself for this person?
>> Yeah. No. Yeah. The Chameleon Heart
lyric is like genius. Very I I'm
obsessed. And it's like you're like a
performer. Like I've seen you perform.
And I feel like it's so cool.
>> Not cool, but like it seems like in your
lyrics you also write about being a
performer in love. And like how do those
two things go hand in hand? Like do you
think they're connected?
>> Oh, totally. I mean,
I think when you're a performer, when
you're a singer, you're really good at
putting a face on, you know? Like,
>> at least I
>> like that's my philosophy as a
performer. Like, no matter how shitty my
day is, no matter how awful I feel,
>> the second I step on stage, I lock in.
Like, there are people there
>> who've paid a lot of money to come see
me or traveled far and they deserve the
best show possible. I've had that
mentality since I was like a child.
>> That's just been practiced into me and I
will continue to practice that
philosophy.
>> Um, so I think
I I I think it's in me to give people
what they want a little bit. So like if
a guy comes along and is like
expecting something of me even though
it's not in line with how I am like my
personality I will find a way to morph
myself to become that because I'm also
at the at the true core a people pleaser
>> which I guess what is what cautionary
tale is about like it's kind of about
being a people pleaser and putting on
this performance and like kind of
pretending to be someone else to
>> make this person feel
>> more safe
>> or better.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> and fall more in love with you.
>> Yeah. But then you have a song like
Tough Luck, which um
>> should we I mean, do I need to play
that?
>> I've I've heard it many times. Um
>> Tough Luck is a fun one.
>> Well, with that song, I feel like that's
the song where I was really like, "Oh,
this is a new sound."
>> Um and it's incredible. And that like
really shows your sass and just like
your wit and you're like, "No, this man
was
>> was really shitty." Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, tough luck was I think I
wanted to show my angry side. Like
>> there are those moments where I'm like
>> where I don't find the empathy, I guess.
>> Yes.
>> They don't last for long, but in those
moments I'm like, "Okay, Better
write a song."
>> Yeah. Um, but yeah, I I felt really
betrayed in a way and and
I mean it it's it was quite plain and
simple like somebody had been mean to me
in a way that I like didn't even think
happened.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I I thought that like only happened
in movies,
>> right?
>> And I think
like this this person's insecurity got
the best of him.
I've like analyzed it a lot obviously.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> But um
>> do you want to go more into detail about
that experience or
>> Sure. I mean I kind of you know wanted
to believe
that there was like a lot of good
intention and and I think this guy was
just like
I don't know. He was just like honestly
the worst.
>> Yeah.
>> Just like I mean you don't need to
explain. It's such a it's such an
important thing to go through because
like it really like
>> I knew what I wanted the second I
emerged out of that relationship.
>> And
yeah, I don't know. I I just want to
show the world that I have I harbor
rage.
>> I harbor anger. And that's okay. That
doesn't make you
>> a bad person. It doesn't make you
>> improper.
>> Like I think
>> I am
>> sassy, you know. Oh my god, I literally
sound like that Miranda again.
>> I do cuss a little.
>> I do cuss. I am sassy.
>> I am a little sassy. Um
>> that's literally
I love Miranda Cosgrove. I'll honestly
take it. I'll honestly take it.
>> But um I I think there's a there's a
level of humor in a lot of my songs and
I have a very distinct sense of humor
and I love plugging that into the music.
And I think, you know, Tough Luck is
just one long sarcastic song.
>> Yes.
>> And I got to put all of my thoughts into
it that I
>> honestly never dared to say.
>> Like I I never said any of this to his
face.
>> Yeah.
>> And it scared the out of me.
>> And like
I Yeah. I guess I wanted to protect his
feelings and maybe this isn't the nice
way for it to get out
>> via song. I don't know. There's like a
level of ambiguity to songs, I guess,
>> but it's also like who cares about him?
Whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, but yeah, I I just like I wanted to
write an angry song like
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> it's not the I mean
>> the whole arrangement was so fun to make
for this song because
>> it How do you transcribe anger
>> into music? How do you do that when
you're known as the hopeless romantic
whimsical
fairy girl?
>> Yeah. Well, I was going to ask like
what's the difference? I'm so like
fascinated by vocal arrangements and for
a song like this, I feel like your voice
>> sounds different. It's still you, but
there's like a different tone to it.
Yeah. And I like what's the difference?
Did you have fun like tapping into that?
>> So much fun tapping into it. Like I
literally just wanted to have fun. And I
think, you know, the the way that it
starts is like very
I, you know, it was it was a really fun
song to find this kind of like middle
ground between like a pop song and a Le
song, right?
>> And I had so much fun like arranging it
in a way that felt true to me musically
>> and fit in with the album and fit in
with my sound, but was also ultimately
just like a crash out song. Yeah.
>> And a song that I got to scream a little
bit in. And
>> you know, I for some reason I've become
known as like a soft singer as well.
>> But when I started singing as as a kid,
I used to belt a lot. Like I was a
belter.
>> And so
>> I guess I felt like I I guess maybe the
material of my lyrics before was just it
wasn't scream worthy, but this was
scream worthy. Um, but you know, the
first verse it opens on just cello and
voice. Like it's very classical and the
the string writing is very like inspired
by like late romantic composers, which
is like
>> such a fun little Easter egg for those
who care. If you don't, it's fine. But
like I love plugging like super
>> kind of fun
>> um music that I love like inspirations
for music that I love into something
that is like a pop song.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so it opens on like just strings and
has all this kind of like
dense like tensiony movement. Um, but we
had so much fun like kind of like
working with like swells like you know I
sing the lyrics. Um,
wait
you you beg me to be silent and it's
like with the silent like the cellos
like grow and it goes
>> and it just like closes up and that
silence that's like that's like word
painting. That's like musical word
painting. It makes the lyric feel so
much more intense.
>> And
yeah, and then with every verse we add
more elements, more drums, more strings.
>> And then by the bridge, it's like we add
electric guitar, and it becomes this
really like funny but fun, loud mish
mash of sounds
>> that
>> I feel like I've never gotten to do, but
I had so much fun doing. Yeah.
>> And then it kind of goes back down and
it ends on just cello and voice again.
>> And it was so fun to create this swell
of a song cuz it was
>> I don't know. It's weird. It's super
weird. Like I've I definitely haven't
heard many songs
>> that do that. And I was definitely a
little nervous for fans to hear it cuz I
was like it's definitely different but
it's also in a weird way the most me
I've ever felt.
>> Yes. And it's been very wellreceived.
like the fans are loving it.
>> I don't know. We we teased the bridge
first and I feel like people are like,
"Wait, what?" Like this is we've never
heard you like this before. And it was
>> it was fun to do that. Like
>> I've never
>> I've never been interested in making
albums and songs that sound just like
the last, you know?
>> Yeah. Um you talked about like the
noise.
>> Yeah. There is a song I need to refresh
myself where there's noise that like
cuts in and out.
>> I mean, this is a perfect
>> Yes,
>> I I know which one it is. I mean, this
is the final song on the album,
>> right? Yes. Tell me all that went in to
making that song. Just everything.
>> So, I wrote this song. It was the first
song I wrote for the album
>> and I wrote it
>> really
>> in a moment. Yeah. It was It's funny how
I tend to start with the end.
>> Yeah.
>> But
>> yeah, I wrote it about feeling kind of
like
scared that I was going to it up,
>> like really mess it up. And
>> I finally had this beautiful thing in
front of me, this beautiful thing in my
hand, and I was scared I was going to
drop it. Like I was scared I was going
to sabotage it. that my
anxiety and my inner thoughts and my
head spinning would get in the way of
something beautiful which in turn
>> makes me spin even more.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like an overinker catastrophe
anxious song.
>> Yeah. and those like string disturbances
like I wanted that to
kind of paint how it feels like to have
anxious thoughts and have them kind of
attack you out of nowhere even in your
most peaceful moments.
>> So
>> yeah,
>> and I kind of Yeah, I wanted to end the
album.
>> I literally keep burping. I um I wanted
to end the album on that. Just like this
kind of mishmash of everything. Just
>> throw every everything in the fire.
Everything that I expect of myself,
everything that
>> my my fans or my family or the world
expects from me, I just like wanted to
throw it all in the in the dumpster.
>> Yeah. Um what is the process of the
noise like all of that noise coming in
in the studio? like what's the process
of making that noise and like putting it
all together in a way that like sounds
noisy but it still sounds good. Well,
it's all rooted in this melody idea that
I had,
>> which sounded really wonky, which is
>> and
yeah, it's we made this like big coral
arrangement to it that made made it
sound kind of like a really scary scene
in a film.
>> And then I was like, I want drums on it.
Like I want like rock drums on it. So we
did that and then I was like I I want to
hear like screeching scratching sounds.
>> So we had my bass player Dario come in
and just like hack at his double bass
and I
>> you know tried to play the cello in
every wrong way possible.
>> Um yeah, we were literally just banging
on every single instrument we could find
in the studio. It was so fun. I have
videos of it actually where I was just
like banging on the piano, banging on
the toles, like I was banging on the
drums. I'm not a drummer, but I really
wanted to just
>> I don't know, hit things.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And was it obvious that this
was like the closer on the album? Yeah.
>> Yeah, it definitely was. I was like,
okay. And it and it had the perfect
album title in it, which is it's a
matter of time. Yeah.
>> And it was yeah, it was kind of my way
of just,
you know, how I talked about the whole
album being like
this bearing of of my soul and this
bearing of of who I am to the core. And
>> Yeah.
>> And that's what it is. It's like it's a
matter of time until you find out I'm
crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> It's a matter of time until you find out
who I truly am to the core, which is a
person that's going to this up.
>> Yeah. which are you like navigating that
still in your present day? Is that still
something you feel or have you
>> not really
>> settled into it?
>> I've definitely settled into it.
>> Yeah.
>> In this specific instance, but
>> I mean it's it's a it's ultimately a
song about being
anxious.
>> Yeah.
>> And like I'm I'm scared I'm going to
sabotage my career, you know? It's a
beautiful thing and I care. Anything I
care a lot about
>> is at risk of being sabotaged
>> and I kind of think, you know, that's
what
that's what I was writing about, you
know,
>> and I feel like it's also like it's the
end of this chapter, but it also like
sets up for a perfect beginning of your
next chapter.
>> Yeah. And like who knows what that's
going to be.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
>> It's just going to be loud.
>> Yes. And it was loud and it was perfect
though. It's just like I love when songs
are so loud and so noisy, but they still
just like hit the right spots in your
ear. And I think that's this.
>> Yeah. I wanted it to be shocking. Like I
want
>> I want people to be listening to this
beautiful song, this haunting,
>> delicate thing
>> that sounds so so very me.
>> Yeah.
>> And then be kind of like hit sideways
with like a wall of sound.
>> Yeah. Well, you achieved. So you
achieved. Um, I said I really wanted to
talk about Cuckoo.
>> Okay, let's go to that.
>> So, Cuckoo Ballet is an interlude and
Spencer and I wrote it and it's
comprised of melodies from the album.
>> Okay.
>> And it's really I love it. That is one
of my favorites.
>> Me, too. I usually really gravitate
towards like instrumentals like for
example like on preachers's daughter
Ethel Kane televangelism is like one of
my favorite songs and I feel like
>> I just like am so intrigued as to what
the story is behind songs without
>> any lyrics like what story were you
trying
>> I mean
>> to tell here
>> I think all of my favorite ballets
operas musicals have an interlude they
have a prelude they have these musical
moments that are almost like you hit
pause on the story for a second and
you're just using the music to kind of
put you in the in the place like and
>> I really wanted to have a piece that
truly like paid homage to my classical
roots and something that I was playing
cello in and something that
>> kind of felt otherworldly and made you
feel like you were maybe watching a
ballet or an opera or a movie or
Um,
>> but yeah, really what it is is is
scoring. I mean, Spencer did such an
amazing job on this. And
>> we have like I think it's it's cello,
violin,
like lots of like random little like
clock sound like percussionist like
cowbells that make clock sounds.
>> There's chest. There's harp.
>> Yeah.
>> And chest is like the toy to toy piano
sounding thing that sounds really bright
and fun.
And there's like obo and clarinet and
it's really like
Yeah, it's it's so fun because you have
like melodies from Clockwork, Carousel,
Snow White, Tough Luck, everything is
hidden in there,
>> but it's like warped in a way that
>> you can't always tell.
>> Yeah.
>> And yeah, I love it so much. It's like
very inspired by by like French
impressionist music. Um, some of my
favorite composers are WC and Rell who
like
>> they're like the kings of musical
painting
>> like of of taking an image and kind of
smudging it a little bit but
>> you know
>> sometimes it sounds a little weird but
>> then it something resolves and it sounds
really perfect and
>> so yeah.
>> Yeah, I definitely see that. I told you
to me I hear like the sound of music.
It's one of my favorite movies and I
just feel Yeah. I feel like when I heard
it, I pictured the scene of them doing
like the puppet show and just like
honestly the whole movie.
>> Absolutely. I mean,
>> the Sound of Music is a perfect example
of the kind of
>> musical that I'm talking about, right?
It has that
>> grand interlude that gives you chills
and it h No, the grand prelude, sorry.
Like the overture, the starting it
literally has an overture
>> and then it has like musical moments in
the middle and
>> that kind of like keep the story going.
And I really do view this album as a
musical.
>> So, it's really um
>> yeah, I'm I'm so I I love plugging
musical moments like this into my albums
cuz I just don't think
>> we hear enough of them. But this one's
very intentional. Like
>> it I didn't put an interlude in there
for no reason. Like I care as much about
this
>> track as much as I care about the
others.
>> Yeah, absolutely. That makes me so
excited for tour because just you saying
that it's theatrical and like very
musical vibes. I can't wait to see what
you do with this album.
>> It's definitely very
>> It's definitely very like whimsical and
larger than life and
>> um taking a lot of inspiration from the
ballets and musicals and operas that we
love.
>> I'm so excited. Um and then
>> was there another song you want to hear?
I really want to talk about I've
listened to it a couple times. So, but
forget me not.
>> I mean, we can just go straight to
talking about that.
>> Yeah. Cuz I feel like I have
>> Yeah.
>> enough of a I wrote beautiful in all
caps.
>> Oh,
>> and the Icelandic. I want to talk about
I I have been homesick so many times in
my life because I've moved Yeah.
>> around to like three different places,
which isn't a lot, but the first one was
really hard. It was like I was 12 and I
was moving like from all my friends. And
I feel like this brought me back to that
feeling or even when I moved for
university
>> and um yeah, I feel like you captured
homesickness so perfectly in this song.
And I just want you to take talk about
Iceland and talk about
>> Yeah.
>> using
like speaking Icelandic in this song
like just everything that
>> Yeah. I mean
I yeah I grew up I grew up in Iceland
and it's
>> within the walls of the Iceland Symphony
um which is the orchestra that I
>> I read
>> recorded this with and my mom's actually
in the Iceland Symphony so it was really
fun.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I really wanted to write a song
about this feeling of homesickness and
also this feeling of losing your
original identity a little bit. kind of
just the the immigration experience a
little bit. Like
>> with every day that I live in America, I
feel a little little bit less
>> Icelandic,
>> but then I also feel
completely Icelandic as well. And I just
I don't know. I just want to write an
ode to the country and
>> I was missing home so much and felt like
I had given up
my whole Icelandic life.
>> Yeah. to chase this dream that I have
this this revery.
>> Um, so it was really a fun song for me
to write. It was based on or I wanted it
to sound like old Icelandic folk songs.
>> Like there's a very distinct um melodic
sound
to there's a very distinct
>> type of sound to Icelandic folk songs.
um like the harmony writing and the the
the
>> um the melodies.
>> So, and I knew immediately that I wanted
it to be with orchestra, but I I also I
wanted the song to be a love song as
well. Like I wanted people to I want
people to listen to it and think it's a
love song at first because it is a love
song to my country. Mhm.
>> And I've never written in Icelandic
before.
>> And I'll definitely write a full song in
Icelandic at some point, but it just
>> that last line, which is
flying away from here. But it sounds
like a bird flying. Yeah.
>> Not like an airplane plane. Like though
I'm flying away from here.
>> Um, never forget me, my love.
>> And I'm kind of referring to Iceland as
my love.
>> My love. Yeah.
>> And you know the lyrics singing about
like the bends in its body and the the
kiss the chill of a kiss on the cheek.
Like
>> I'm talking about the black sand.
Exactly. I'm like I really something
that really
is really prevalent in Icelandic folk
tunes and the lyrics in Icelandic folk
tunes is this use of personification.
>> Yeah.
>> Um like the sun is smiling
>> or
the rocks are you know dancing I don't
know like or the rocks are like yeah the
ocean is dancing.
>> Yeah. And so I really wanted to
in the lyrics of this song as like to
pay tribute to that kind of lyrical
writing.
>> Yeah.
>> Though most of it is in English, I
wanted to kind of say oh the wind
kissing you on the cheek and the the
bends of the body and you know Iceland
is very like you know
>> bendy like the way it's shaped. Um, but
yeah, I think there's one lyric there
that is like you said the I'm just a
girl on the I'm still just the girl on
the black sand beach and
>> and it's like I guess to me I wrote that
because I was feeling so exposed to the
world in a way and like the world had
become so big like
>> I've been taking full like circles
around the earth like twice a year
>> doing tours and stuff and it's so much
fun and I've seen so many people, but
ultimately at the end of the day, I go
to bed and I just I feel like I'm still
just a girl sitting on a black sand
beach.
>> Yeah. And I feel like you already
touched on it, but like the title, do
you want to talk about like the title of
the song a bit, like Forget Me Not and
the feelings associated with that?
>> Yeah. I mean, I had a really tough time
figuring out the title for this song
actually because
>> it felt like so many points were being,
you know, I was like touching on so many
things. I didn't want to necessarily
write a song about
um I didn't necessarily want to write a
song about just I didn't want to call it
like never forget me or or an Icelandic
title like that didn't feel like the
right thing. Mhm.
>> So, I was just thinking about like the
landscape and, you know, the flowers and
and I was I don't know. I was like
riffing with my twin sister and my
friend Carmen and we were like what what
sounds like the right thing like what's
the right word for this
>> and I was like never forget me
>> for forget me and then and then we were
like wait for forget me not and like
>> that is how or no it came from actually
cuz the lyric is claim so I was like
should we call it climtore and Carmen
was like wait
is a um is a forget me not. Okay.
>> It's like literally the same thing. It's
just like the word
>> all the words put into one
>> okay
>> word.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> and I don't I don't know. I didn't want
to have just like a random Icelandic
word either.
>> So, it became forget me now.
>> Very beautiful.
>> But, you know, there's a lot of like
touches of blue and purple like in the
visuals of the album. And that's kind of
like those are the colors I see when I
think about the album and when I listen
to the album. So it all just felt very
perfect. So
>> yeah, which the album cover gives those
colors as well.
>> Yeah. I mean with the album cover and
all the visuals for the album and music
videos and everything. I
I I think I had spent so much time
chasing beauty and elegance and
perfection and
>> you know I kind of was just tired of it.
Like
>> you'll never fulfill yourself if you're
chasing beauty because beauty trends are
changing every 10 minutes. It's like
insane. You'll never catch up. Mhm.
>> And so I was just like I wanted to have
an album cover and visuals that
told a story like I was like what what's
interesting? What has like a flicker of
emotion in it or a you know some sort of
smirk or some I don't know something
that looks like it's conveying a story
>> or conveying an emotion correctly not
just serving face or whatever you know
>> serving face.
>> No, like we have Instagram, we have Tik
Tok, we can serve face every single day
if we want to. Exactly.
>> Um I try to put that into practice.
every day I'm serving face.
>> No, literally.
>> And like Yeah. I think
>> Yeah.
>> I just was tired of trying to always
look beautiful
>> and I wanted to do something weird cuz
I've always been a little odd.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I thought that that was Yeah. I was
just going to embrace it like
>> whatever. Like
>> And Yuna is your creative director.
>> Yes. Sonia did the most amazing job on
all the visuals. She was like, she had
such a clear vision for it that so
closely aligned with what I wanted, she
was just able to like
>> bring it to this like tangible world.
Exactly.
>> And
>> a world is really what it is, you know?
It's
>> it's a complete like
kind of world that you step into. like
Leand literally she's created Lelay Land
>> and it's Yeah, it's so fun to get to
work with her because it's
>> she's the right there. So, this is
awkward but whatever. She's not
listening.
>> Hey,
>> we're talking about you.
>> We're talking about you.
It's such a blessing to get to work with
her because
>> I
have such a clear vision for what I want
and
>> honesty is at the very crux of it
>> and
>> Yuna gets me and is me in many ways like
we are so similar and have the same
references and the same things that make
us excited or we're passionate about the
same things. So working with her is so
amazing cuz I just I feel like
she is like this extension of me that is
so much better at
>> like at um verbalizing also like the
things that I want you know like I'll
have this idea in my head that is like a
vision and I don't know how to
completely say it and she will
>> make that happen so well.
>> It's very special a special connection
with your twin. It is.
>> Um, the last thing I want to talk about
before it gets darkened, you know, is
Mr. Eclectic, cuz we didn't talk about
that.
>> I feel like we must address I was
listening to this song and I said that's
not her singing the background vocals.
Do you want to share who that is?
>> Yes, that is Miss Claro. Um,
>> everyone give it up for Claro.
>> Everyone give it up for She is genuinely
one of my favorite people that I met. I
met her at Electric Lady. I was
recording it there and yeah, she was in
the next door room at Electric Lady and
I was like, "Wait, do you want to hang
out?" And so we hung out a bit and I I
think she has like the same appreciation
as I have for like Bosanova. So I was
like,
>> "Would you want to do BGVs on this
song?" And she was down and it was
honestly the best night ever. We like
>> just like toyed around with all these
like beautiful vintage microphones and
we're making all these like fun like
percussive sounds and
>> and drinking wine and it was Yeah, she's
so talented and has such a beautiful
voice
>> and her like
>> her music knowledge goes so deep
>> and
>> I was so it was so fun just like nerding
out with her and talking about our
favorite music and yeah and also just
like she gave me like the best like
artist advice and was just so I don't
know it made me love being an artist. I
think
>> we worked on this song at a time where I
was
kind of I don't know, I was getting
stressed. I was like, "Oh I have
another album to do." And like all of a
sudden the pressure is really high. Like
there's so many more people watching
this time around. And she really gave me
the
the confidence to just hearing her talk
about her process and her
>> music gave me the confidence to just
like own my music and just be like
whatever and you know put a middle
finger to
>> anybody who doesn't support and just
>> you know do me exactly how I want to do
it.
>> Yeah.
>> So it was really
in that studio. It was
>> must have been a crazy
>> It was honestly so fun. Oh my god. She
like took her flute out and was playing
flute
>> and I was like playing cello and
honestly it was like a scene in a movie.
It was
>> it was really really special and it's
made this song extra extra special and
>> her beautiful voice.
>> Yeah.
>> I assume you would work with her again.
>> Oh my god. I would in a heartbeat. I I
want to write something with her like
from scratch. Yeah,
>> this song was one that I honestly I
think it was the second song that I
wrote for the album, but
>> I wanted to write a song about
>> I don't know like the guys who like
approach me or my sister and are like
>> talking about like literature and like
composers and poets and stuff. I was
going to say
>> and I'm like I don't talk to me about
composers,
>> right? Cuz
>> you don't know what you're talking
about.
>> You're well versed. Yeah,
>> I am. Um, I was going to ask cuz like
name dropping Edgar Allan Pose like
specific like is there is that like a
specific lyric or is it more just like
general that type of man?
>> That type of man, you know, the kind of
the depressed poet I think was top of
mind like we all know a guy who like
reads Edgar Allan Poe as a personality
trait.
>> Um, which is fine honestly. Maybe I'm
being mean, maybe I'm being harsh, but I
do think it's funny.
>> Yeah. when they like start to talk like
classical music to me and I'm like, "Do
you know who you're talking to? Like you
think you're so interesting. You think
you're so eclectic. You think that
you're Mr. Eclectic Alan Poe?"
>> But really, you're not. It's a costume,
>> right? Yeah. And I love the This is the
song where you straight up call the man
a poser if I'm not mistaken. Yes, I do.
>> I really liked that. Like, get him
again. Yes.
>> Yeah. you know.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> We can tell Yes. when loving Edgar Alan
Poe is true of your
>> Yeah.
>> true spirit, you know, of true of your
soul or if it's just a costume.
>> Mhm. I completely agree. It's the most
obvious.
>> It's free to see through.
>> It's free to sit outside a cafe with an
open book.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's theater really. It's a performance.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Um, is there anything
else you want to share or say or
anything you want to get off your chest
about the album?
>> Um,
I don't know honestly. Like I think the
only song we haven't really played
through is or talked about is Carousel.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> And I'd love to talk about it a little
bit.
>> Yes.
>> Super cute. Super Parisian sounding. I
feel like there's little Yeah. moments
in there.
>> Exactly. I was like I spent a lot of
time in Paris last year and
>> I definitely was was walking around and
seeing all these like old carousels and
like I was like wow
>> like
>> the amount of stories that have passed
through that.
>> Yeah. Um, but I was kind of I used a car
the carousel kind of as like this
metaphor for what I felt like my life
was like um for a bit last year where I
was like
>> just spinning round and round like I was
moving but not going anywhere.
>> Yeah.
>> And I was kind of
I The song is about anxiety. Like it's
about it's about letting someone into
your life
when you know you're not perfect.
>> Yeah.
>> It's it's about
feeling sorry for bringing someone into
this like circus
>> Yeah.
>> clown town that I have in my life. Like
I was like I'm so sorry. Like and and
the tether me to your ground lyric is
like
>> is like can you break this spell? like
can you break me out of this like
>> crazy life mental cycle that I'm in and
just like give me sturdy ground and be
the sturdy ground for me.
>> Is that like someone something you would
like say to someone directly or is that
the type of thing you can only say in a
song where you're like asking someone to
ground you? I think this was like one of
those songs where I played played in the
song and I was like,
>> "Yeah,
>> yeah,
>> yeah, yeah."
>> Um, yeah. I I this one for me was just
like I wanted it to be this
almost like this image, you know, like a
like a painting in a museum that you
pass and see and it's like vivid and
full of color. Like I want people to be
able to close their eyes and and know
exactly where they are. I'm so happy
that you like
>> immediately were like it sounds like you
know this like Parisian thing and we had
>> accordion on it
>> which was very intentional cuz we wanted
to create that kind of like moment in a
park and
>> one of my favorite classical pieces ever
is this piece called
>> pictures at an exhibition
>> and it's literally composed it's by um a
composer called Muski
>> okay
>> and he literally composed little pieces
from photos or p from paintings at an
exhibition.
>> Yeah.
>> And the way that he managed to step into
full worlds
>> with music. I was like so inspired by
that and I was like, I want
>> I want my music to sound like that where
you step into a painting and you close
your eyes and you know exactly where you
are.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Having you talk about
atmosphere makes me interested. Like if
you were to lay a perfect picture of
like someone listening to this album for
the first time and like the setting they
were in, what they were doing, like what
the whole vibe and atmosphere would be,
what would you like think would be the
perfect situation to be listening to
this album?
>> Perfect situation.
>> Oh my god. I honestly don't even know
like
>> cuz it is so
different. Like it's so subjective
>> where people feel the most comfortable,
right?
>> Um
>> I think for me like on a walk.
>> Yeah.
>> Like I think that's like the prime place
to hear music is just like with
headphones on a walk.
>> Yeah. Um
or like on a train or a plane or
something like in transport like
>> somewhere you where you can
>> somewhere where there's movement.
>> Yes. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> So true. Um and then you mentioned
Paris. Was there like one place where
you wrote most of this album or was it
all over the place?
>> It was kind of all over the place. Like
I my last album was very LA oriented. It
was like me singing about moving to LA
and being in California. This album was
>> written kind of
>> I would say mostly in Iceland honestly.
Yeah.
>> Between Iceland, New York,
>> Japan, like Australia and LA. Like it's
I was on a world tour, so the music went
on a world tour with me.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Well,
>> is that it?
>> I feel like those are
>> I feel like we've gotten
>> Yeah.
>> a lot.
>> I think those are all the songs and all
the questions
>> I had.
>> Well, thank you so much.
>> So, do we do like a little outro? Like,
>> should we do an outro? Um,
>> I feel like you should lead lead the
charge on this.
>> Okay. Um, I mean, hearing you talk about
everything is just so special and this
was like such an experience for me.
you're so intelligent and so intentional
with the music you're making and just
hearing you nerd out as you said about
these things is just such a joy. Um, so
thank you for letting me
>> ask you these questions and thank you
for being vulnerable and sharing all of
this stuff.
>> Of course. Thank you so much for taking
the time to listen and like caring. It
means so much. And
>> of course,
>> all your questions were like honestly
got me thinking. I'm like, "Okay, I'm
glad. This is good." Yeah. Yeah.
>> I'm glad. But yeah, I I can't wait for
everyone to hear this album cuz it's so
special. And
>> thank you.
>> I hope you feel the same way.
>> I I love it so much. I think it's my I
think it's my best work so far. So,
>> yeah. I agree. Favorite album of yours.
I agree. Yeah. Um but yeah.
>> Well, bye.
>> Yay.